本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
見てくださいグンテ将軍
Look, General Geun-tae.
That dance is very interesting.
あの踊り 面白いですね
陛下
My king...
確か 俺は模擬選に出るはずですが
I believe I'm supposed to appear in the mock battle.
なんですか このひらひらした服は
So what are these frilly clothes?
お祭りの衣装ですよ
They're festival clothes.
今日はグンテ将軍が主役ですし
You're the star today, General Geun-tae.
綺麗ですよね
Aren't they beautiful?
異国の衣装見たい
They look foreign!
とても戦闘に向いてる服とは思えん
These clothes aren't suited for battle.
Especially these stones! They're in the way.
特にこの石 邪魔だ
Lord Geun-tae!
グンテ様
ユウノ
Yuno...
What should I do?
どうしよう
Blush
すごくすごくすごく可愛い
You look really cute!
You'd better not grab me and call me cute.
お前 俺をつかまえて 可愛いとか言うな
その衣装 私が見立てたの
I chose that outfit for you.
It was you?!
お前か
Damn you.
Oh, my.
陛下 これは妻のユウノ
King, this is my wife, Yuno.
ユウノさん こんにちは
Lady Yuno, hello.
まぁ 陛下も可愛い
You look cute too.
How do you know him?!
なんで知り合いだ
陛下は私のお茶を気に入って下さったの
The king said he likes my tea.
もうすっかりお茶飲み友たちよ
We're tea buddies now.
Right?
ね
When did this happen?
知らぬ間に
ね
Right.
グンテ様がこの一週間
陛下をほったらかしにしてたからですよ
It's your fault for ignoring the king all week, Lord Geun-tae.
The sound of festival music.
The voices of my tribe.
War games of a people who have forgotten what war is, in a time when black shadows loom over the kingdom.
黒い影 忍び寄る国の
戦争を忘れた人々の戦争ごっこ
こんなことをしている場合か
This isn't the time for these things.
O maiden!
otome yo
Flare up in the dawning sun!
akatsuki ni moeagare
I want to tear off the guise of the ignorant
muchi de kayowaku mamorareru dake no
Frail protected princess and live
hime nugisutete watashi wa ikitai
To conquer the color of the burning dawn
mukashi yori sukoshi dake suki ni nareta
That I've recently started enjoying
akatsuki no sora no iro nabikase
With strength and commanding presence
rinzen to tsuyoku
I strive to be someone I'm proud of
kedakaku sora wo miagete
And looking up idealistically to the sky
hokoreru jibun ni narou
To protect, to love, to stand my ground
mamori aishi tsuranuku
I won't allow myself to lose anything again
keshite ubawasenai
Like a noble flower
kedakai hana no you ni
With single-minded passion
hitamuki na jounetsu de
Even if faced with a cruel fate
zankoku na sadame sae
I will push through
kirihiraite miseru kara
Now, for this mock battle,
では
この模擬戦は赤軍 白軍に分かれ
you will be divided into red and white armies,
Episode 16:      War Games
木刀にて相手の皿を割るという戦いです
and you must break opponents' plates with wooden swords.
ジュド将軍 もう装着済み
General Ju-doh, you're already wearing yours?
クソマジメだ
You're really taking this seriously.
赤軍はグンテ将軍 白軍は私を王とし
General Geun-tae and I will be the kings of the red and white armies respectively.
他は貴族 平民の階級に分かれています
The other participants are divided into nobles and commoners.
平民の皿を一点 貴族の皿は五点 王の皿を十点とし
A commoner's plate is worth one point,
a noble's is worth five, and a king's is worth ten.
多くの皿を割って点を稼いだ軍が勝ち
The army that earns the most points wins.
すべての皿が割られると終了です
If all an army's plates are broken, the battle ends.
ここで注意しなければならないのは階級です
You must pay close attention to the ranks.
同じ階級同士は対等に戦えます
People of the same rank fight as equals.
Noble
King
王は貴族の皿は割れますが 平民の皿は割れません
A king can break a noble's plate, but he cannot break a commoner's.
King
Noble
Commoner
King
Noble
Commoner
King
Noble
Commoner
King
貴族は平民の皿は割れますが 王の皿は割れません
Noble
Nobles can break a commoner's plate, but they cannot break a king's.
Commoner
Noble
King
平民は王の皿は割れますが 貴族の皿は割れません
Noble
Commoners can break a king's plate, but they cannot break a noble's.
Commoner
King
Noble
Commoner
割られた人は敵の捕虜になりますが
Prisoner
Those whose plates are broken become the opposing army's prisoners,
and may be revived only once by receiving spare plates from their allies.
見方が予備の皿を捕虜に渡せば一回だけ復活できます
Take this!
Revived
Breaking the ranking rules or deliberately hitting
階級の決まりを無視したり
木刀で皿以外をわざと攻撃すると失格ですかか
something other than a plate with your sword will result in disqualification.
ケガしないで 頑張ってくださいね
Play safe and fight hard.
Fuzzy Wuzzy
なんとも気合いの入らんお方よ
What an uninspiring man.
同感だ
I agree.
For once, we agree.
珍しく意見が合ったな
This is meant to be a competition, but can the king even fight?
大体試合と言うが 陛下は武術はお出来になるのか
陛下の幼馴染であった雷獣 あいつは天才だった
The Thunder Beast, the king's childhood friend, was a prodigy.
武人は実践において経験を積み 力を磨いてゆくのだが
A warrior hones his skills by gaining experience on the battlefield,
あやつは碌に戦場も知らずして一騎当千の力を持っていた
but he possessed the strength of a thousand men, without ever truly going to war.
だが陛下の武術の腕は噂にも聞かん
However, I haven't even heard rumors of the king's combat prowess.
見たところ 色も白く腕も細い
He's pale, and his arms are thin.
雷獣が虎なら 陛下はさながらウサギだな
If the Thunder Beast is a tiger, then the king is a rabbit.
誰か貴様などと意見が合うか
I would never agree with you!
Huh? What are you so upset about?
なんにを怒ってるんじゃ
Are you so blinded by natural talent?
天賦の才がそんなに輝かしいか
大地を引き裂く勢いで現れた虎ばかりに目を奪われ
You're dazzled by the tiger's earth-shattering appearance,
お前が言うウサギが本当はどんな姿をしているかも分からんとは
and you fail to see the true nature of the so-called rabbit.
貴様も 貴様に心酔するここの部族共も
Both you and your adoring tribesmen are blind!
揃いも揃って節穴だな
Lord Geun-tae!
グンテ様...
さて皆様 お待たせしました
Thank you for waiting, everyone.
The red-versus-white, plate-smashing battle will now begin!
赤白対抗皿割り合戦 始まります
I, Cheol-ran, Lord Geun-tae's personal attendant, will be your commentator!
実況は私 グンテ様のお世話役のチョルランがお送りします
東門 燃える炎は正義の色
The fire blazing at the eastern gate is the color of righteousness.
我らが英雄グンテ様率いる赤軍
Our hero, Lord Geun-tae, leads the red army!
西門 舞いおりた美しき天の使い
At the western gate is a beautiful angel, descended from the heavens.
空の部族スウォン陛下率いる白軍
King Su-won of the Sky Tribe leads the white army.
What?
The king?
陛下 陛下って
The People Were Uninformed
Did he say the king?
Should I have said that?
いいのかな 言っちゃいましたよ
The People Were Uninformed
狙撃されても我々は責任持ちませんからね
Don't blame us if you end up with an arrow in your chest.
The People Were Uninformed
The plates on their heads are so cute!
頭のお皿可愛い
The People Were Uninformed
なんだ ジュドのやつ
What's Ju-doh's problem?
いつも悪態ついているのはお前だろうに
He's the one who's always criticizing the king.
Hey, the more you look, the more he resembles a rabbit.
ほれ 見れば見るほどウサギじゃねぇか
ウサギでなければリスか
If he isn't a rabbit, he must be a squirrel.
どちらにしろ戦場では虎に食い殺されるだけよ
Either way, he'll get eaten by the tiger on the battlefield.
まぁいい お手並み拝見と行こう
Whatever. Let's see what he can do.
開戦
Begin!
What's this?!
白軍いきなり大胆な戦略
The white army makes a sudden, bold move!
Their king, King Su-won, is standing in the center!
王のスウォン陛下が中央に出ています
Oh?
さすがは我らがグンテ様 受けて立ちました
Our Lord Geun-tae is meeting their challenge!
者とも 俺に続け
Men, follow me!
赤軍の鬨の声が場内に響き渡ります
The red army's battle cry rings throughout the arena!
Though nothing has happened yet, the audience is exhilarated!
まだ何もしてないのに客席も尋常じゃない盛り上がりです
さてスウォン陛下 真っ向勝負
King Su-won prepares for a direct confrontation!
What?
Huh?
なんと スウォン陛下 逃げました
What's this? King Su-won has fled!
勇ましく勝負を受けたグンテ様 肩すかしです
Lord Geun-tae, who gallantly accepted his challenge, is disappointed!
逃げるだと 何たる腰抜け
You're running? What a coward!
しかし 虚をついて白軍の平民がグンテ様に迫る
But the commoners of the white army catch Lord Geun-tae off guard and attack!
グンテ様 危ない
Lord Geun-tae, watch out!
Lord Geun-tae!
グンテ様
お下がりください
Please step back.
我々はこのまま赤軍の捕虜となります
We will become prisoners of the red army.
元々 私等は人数合わせで白軍に入れられた地の部族
We're Earth Tribe members, forced to join the white army for the sake of numbers.
Our hearts belong with the red army.
心は赤軍にあります
あなた様に勝利を
Victory to Lord Geun-tae!
グンテ様万歳
Long live Lord Geun-tae!
I don't want you fools!
いらんわ このアホ共
お前ら 俺を愚弄するのか
Are you mocking me?
不正しなければ 俺が負けるとでも
You think I can't win unless I cheat?
勝負を投げるなど俺が最も嫌うところ
There is nothing I despise more than giving up.
そんな腑抜けた忠誠心など俺はいらん
I don't need your cowardly loyalty!
犬にでも食わせちまえ
Go feed it to the dogs!
泣くな
Don't cry!
改めてグンテ様を誇りに思います
We're just so proud of you, Lord Geun-tae!
我々が愚かでした お許しを
We were fools. Forgive us.
ならば 心を入れ替え
We will mend our ways! And in a fair fight...
正々堂々 あなた様をぶっ倒します
We'll defeat you, sir!
A king cannot attack a commoner.
Crap. They're all commoners.
やべぇ 全員平民
Lord Geun-tae is in trouble!
グンテ様 危うしい
王は平民に刃を向けられません
A king cannot attack commoners!
グンテ様 ご無事で
Lord Geun-tae, are you all right?
Yeah.
A noble of the red army takes out five white commoners at once!
赤軍貴族 白軍平民五名を一気に殲滅
捕虜としました
They are now prisoners, but...
だが
来たか 貴族
So you've come, nobles?
待っていたぞ
I've been waiting for you.
Nobles!
貴族共目
Step forward if you want to die!
死にたい奴は 前に出ろ
グンテ様 白軍貴族を次々と倒していきます
Lord Geun-tae fells one white army noble after another!
By the way, if you kill them, you'll be disqualified!
ちなみに 殺してしまっては 失格ですから
That's it! Draw that expression!
今の 今の顔描いて
That isn't fair, Lady Yuno! I want one as well!
狡い ユウノ様 私も一枚
The white army's King Su-won is still running around the battlefield, pursued by commoners!
白軍王のスウォン陛下 平民達に追われ
いまだ場内を逃げ回っています
In contrast, the red army's General Geun-tae charges forward to strike down his next opponent!
対して赤軍王グンテ将軍
次なる敵を目指して突進
貴族
A noble!
It's white army noble General Han Ju-doh!
これは白軍貴族 ハンジュド将軍
空と地の将軍対決や
It's a showdown between the Sky and Earth generals!
Ju-doh, you're a noble. How dare you raise your sword against a king?
ジュド 貴族の分際で何王に刃向けてんだ
向けているのではない 防御だ
I'm not raising it against you. I'm defending myself.
王の真似事で図に乗るな
You're only pretending to be a king. Don't let it go to your head!
Impressive, General Ju-doh.
さすがはジュド将軍
お前が本来の二刀流でここが戦場であったなら
If you were using your two-sword style and we were on the battlefield,
俺とそいつは今ので真っ二つになっていたかもしれんな
that move might have cut both me and that other guy in half.
興が乗ってきた
This is starting to get interesting.
お前は俺がヤ♂ル
I'll kill you.
単純な男よ
Such a simple man.
それでも王か
And you call yourself a king?
Huh?
ここが戦場ならば
If we were on the battlefield, you would be a fool of a king to look only at me
俺ばかりを見ていて戦況に気づかぬお前は
愚王となるだろう
and not pay attention to your surroundings.
なに
What?
Friendly fire!
自殺点
赤軍同士で皿を割ってしまった
Red soldiers are smashing each other's plates!
なんとスウォン陛下 転んでしまったようです
King Su-won seems to have tripped!
赤軍の振り下ろされた木刀は味方に当たってしまいました
The red soldiers have accidentally struck their own men!
What incredible luck.
なんと言う幸運
この場合 白軍の点として加算されます
These points will be counted in favor of the white army!
幸運だと
Luck?
そしてスウォン陛下
混乱に乗じて赤軍の陣地にグングン入り込む
King Su-won uses the confusion to plunge deeper into the red army's position!
させるか
You aren't going anywhere!
Lord Geun-tae is on the move!
グンテ様も動いた
陛下 覚悟
King, prepare yourself!
King Su-won is in a desperate situation!
スウォン陛下 絶体絶命
What an incredible coincidence!
すごい偶然
A little farther, and he would have broken his plate.
もう少しずれてたら 皿 割れてましたよ
いや 脳天割れてたかも
No, perhaps he would have broken his skull!
なんだ
What?
今 俺を見た
Was he just looking at me?
俺を狙った
Was he aiming for me?
すいません グンテ将軍
I'm sorry, General Geun-tae!
大丈夫ですか
Are you all right?
こやつ 本当にウサギか
Is this man really a rabbit?
すごい偶然
What an incredible coincidence!
スウォン陛下の弾いた木刀がグンテ様の脳天すれすれに落ちた
The wooden sword deflected by King Su-won nearly struck Lord Geun-tae's head!
偶然 いや
A coincidence? No...
狙ったのだ 俺の目の前を
He was aiming right in front of me.
あの目は ウサギか
Are those the eyes of a rabbit?
King Su-won releases the white army prisoners!
スウォン陛下 白軍捕虜達を解放
兵の数では赤軍を上回りましたが
Though they now have more soldiers than the red army,
また皿を割れれば 敵に得点を与えることとなります
if their plates are broken again, that will mean more points for their opponents!
Will this work for them or against them?
吉と出るか 凶と出るか
解放された白軍兵 四方散り散りになって 赤軍に勝負を挑む
The released prisoners scatter to engage the red army!
そして スウォン陛下は
And King Su-won...
まだもや平民い追い回されています
is being chased by commoners again!
なんだ そりゃ
What is he doing?
さっきのは 俺の見間違いか
Was I mistaken?
突風です 砂埃が闘技場を舞う
A sudden gust sends clouds of dust flying throughout the arena!
I can't see.
視界が...
今のは何方の兵だ
Whose soldier was that?
White shadows?
白兵かい
まずい
Damn!
適当に散り散りになってるわけじゃねぇ
They didn't scatter at random.
貴族 平民の混合組に分かれて 赤軍を追い込んでいる
They're attacking the red army with mixed groups of nobles and commoners.
赤軍 バラバラになるな
Red army, stay together!
態勢を立て直す 集まれ
We'll regroup! Come to me!
クソ
Damn it.
How is the white army controlling its forces amid this dust?
白軍はこの中で どうやって兵共の統制を
赤軍...
Red army!
Have you come for my head?
俺の首を取りに来たか
I would never!
そんな 滅相もない
ただ私は陛下が
But the king told us you like heroes who challenge their enemies.
グンテ様は勝負を挑む勇者がお好きだとおっしゃるので
The king?
陛下が
俺の部下の動かし方をよく分かっている
He knows how to motivate my people.
お前ら 砂埃の中でよく動けたな
I'm impressed you were able to move around in this dust.
風が来たら 風上に立つようにと陛下がご指示を
The king instructed us to stand upwind when the wind came.
風を呼んでいたのか
He was expecting the wind?
では この作戦の指示を出しているのも 陛下か
Is your king directing this strategy as well?
は はい
Y-Yes, sir.
俺は 侮り過ぎていた
I underestimated him.
先程の砂嵐後 赤軍の兵は大幅に減ってしまいました
After that sandstorm, the red army's numbers are severely diminished!
Will this be our first and final battle of the kings?
最初で最後の王対決か
グンテ様
Lord Geun-tae...
The king isn't fleeing. He's baiting my men.
陛下は逃げ回ってるのではない 誘導しているのだ
赤軍を殲滅場所へ
He's luring the red army to defeat.
白軍は 地の部族がほとんどの士気が低い連中なのに
The white army is composed primarily of meek Earth Tribe members.
捕虜から復活させて 士気を高め
But they raised their morale by releasing their prisoners
なんだかんだで 上手く動かしてやがる
and are moving effectively, somehow.
ウサギのように逃げ回ると見せかけておいて
He's only pretending to flee like a rabbit.
What is his true nature?
本性はなんだ
General Geun-tae, that hurts!
グンテ将軍 痛いです
口とは裏腹に 俺の刀をしっかり止めていやがる
Despite what he says, he's stopping my blows.
赤軍 まだやられてしまった
The red army has lost more soldiers!
なんと言うことでしょう
How can this be?
Lord Geun-tae is the last remaining member of the red army!
赤軍はグンテ様一人になってしまいました
これでは いかにグンテ様といえども...
Not even Lord Geun-tae can escape this situation.
さて 貴方は一人です グンテ将軍
You're alone, General Geun-tae.
ここは戦場ならば 貴方は確実に死にます
If this place were a battlefield, you would certainly die.
What will you do?
どうしますか
The fleeing rabbit now seems like a hawk fixated on its prey.
逃げ回るだけだったウサギが
今は狙った獲物を逃さぬ鷹に見える
そんな状況だから 相手がでかく見えるか
Does he seem larger because of the situation?
たかだこんな遊びに
Even though it's only a game?
いや そうではない そうではないのだ
No, that's not it. That's not it at all.
一つ提案します
I have a suggestion.
This may be a friendly competition,
試合とはいえ
グンテ将軍が民衆の前で負けては立つ瀬がないでしょう
but if you're defeated in front of your people, you'll lose face.
復活の機会を与えます
I'll grant you a second chance.
捕虜を解放し もう一度勝負をするというのは如何です
Why don't I release the prisoners, so we can battle once more?
断る
I decline your offer.
戦場ならば 死者は蘇らない
On the battlefield, the dead do not come back to life.
例え目の前が千の敵だとて 俺は戦う
Even if a thousand enemies stand before me, I will fight!
面目などを気にして 国が救えるか
Worrying about my reputation will not save the kingdom!
もうたかが遊びではないのだ
This isn't just a game anymore.
これはこの国の王が 仕えるにたる人間かを見定めるため
It's an opportunity for me to determine whether this nation's king is worth serving.
では私がお相手を
Then I will accept your challenge.
束でかかってきても構いませんよ
I don't mind taking you all on!
Lord Geun-tae seemed to be in a desperate situation,
絶体絶命と思われたグンテ様が
陛下と一騎打ちを
but now he's fighting the king one-on-one!
Lord Geun-tae!
グンテ様
He wields his sword calmly against me,
この俺を相手に 冷静な剣捌き
だが それだけでは分からん この王は真の王か否か
but that doesn't tell me enough.
Is this man a true king or not?
You're mine!
もらった
What?
あら
All right! Victory!
やった 勝利
まだ勝ってないけど
He hasn't won yet, though.
グンテ様 勝利です
But Lord Geun-tae is victorious!
I knew our general could do it! He's got it!
さすが我らが将軍 持ってる男
この場で決めました
He has won the battle!
いや さすがはグンテ将軍
That was impressive, General Geun-tae.
You defeated me.
やられちゃいましたね
What was that?
なんですか 今の
やっぱりお強いですね
You truly are strong.
お戯れを
Don't play games.
Uh...
Once more. Stand.
もう一度だ 立て
Wh-What should we do?
ど どうしましょう
だんだん言葉使いが怪しく
He's starting to sound weird.
試合はまだ続いている 行け
The competition isn't over yet. Go.
その後 ついにグンテ将軍の皿が割られ 赤軍は全滅
Later, General Geun-tae's plate was finally broken,
and the red army was annihilated.
しかし 将軍も最後に大暴れ
However, the general didn't go down without a fight.
ただではやられまいと
Refusing to go quietly, he took out four nobles,
貴族四人を倒したため
結果的に白軍を得点で上回り 赤軍が勝利したのです
earning the red army enough points to win.
地心の都では 奇跡の勝利として夜通し宴が催されました
In Chishin, the miraculous victory was celebrated all night.
That festival was fun.
いや 楽しいお祭りでしたね
どうしたんですか グンテ将軍
What's wrong, General Geun-tae?
なにを怒ってるんですか
What are you upset about?
一体 何しにきたんですか 陛下は
Why did you come here, King?
地心城に来て うろうろして
All you did was wander around the castle, have tea with my wife,
and frolic about at a festival.
嫁と茶して 祭りで騒いで 遊んでただけではないですか
グンテ将軍 ジュド将軍に似てきましたね
General Geun-tae, you're starting to sound like General Ju-doh.
一緒にしないで頂きたい
Don't compare him to me!
この王に何かを感じた気がしたが 錯覚か
I thought I sensed something in this king, but was I wrong?
グンテ様 グンテ様
Lord Geun-tae, Lord Geun-tae!
聞いて 聞いて すごいの
Listen to this. It's incredible.
どうした
What is it?
私のお茶を 戒帝国の商団さんが買いたいんですって
Some merchants from the Kai Empire want to buy my tea.
Your tea? You mean this smelly tea?
茶って この臭い茶か
It isn't smelly. It has a floral fragrance!
臭くない お花の香り
戒帝国では お花の香りのお茶がとても好まれるんですって
The people of the Kai Empire love fragrant, floral teas.
Seriously?
まじでか
でもどうしよう
But what should I do?
My tea plantation is too small to supply the Kai Empire.
私の茶畑は戒帝国を相手にするには小さ過ぎるの
As long as you expand gradually, you'll be fine.
大丈夫ですよ 徐々に広げてゆけば
大量に安売りしないで
Instead of selling large amounts cheaply,
地心特産高級茶として売り出せば この都に人が集まります
if you market it as a high-quality specialty tea of Chishin,
people will come to this city.
人は 入手しにくい物ほど 必死で欲しがる生き物ですからね
The more difficult something is to acquire, the more desperately people want it.
Yes, King.
はい 陛下
グンテ様 ウド鉱山が
Lord Geun-tae, Udo Mine is...
ヒデ爺 また落盤か
Elder Hi-dea, did it collapse again?
違う 違うよ
No, it's not that.
We don't have enough workers. We're so busy.
人手が足らねぇんだ 大忙し
大忙し
Busy?
グンテ様が模擬戦で身に着けられてた石があったじゃろ
Remember the stones you wore to the mock battle?
あれの注文が殺到しての
We've received an overwhelming number of orders for them.
Huh? That's impossible.
あ まさが あんな大して輝かない石
Those stones hardly even sparkle.
だから今まで誰も価値があるなんて思ってなかった
That's why no one thought they had any value until now.
だが職人が磨いてみたら なかなかどうして美しい
However, after our artisans polish them, they're quite beautiful.
それよりなにより
More than anything, they're the stones of victory that you wore when you won.
グンテ様が身に着けて勝利された必勝の石
Of course everyone wants them.
そりゃ皆欲しいわな
I've already got my own.
ちなみに 俺はもう持ってる
Why would you wear that?
じじがあんなもんつけて どうすんだ
Doesn't it look cool?
格好よかろ
いいな 私も欲しい
How pretty. I want one as well.
The tea was delicious.
あぁ お茶美味しかった
Mister Hi-dea, I'd like one, too!
ヒデさん 私の分も
General Ju-doh, should we go?
ジュド将軍 そろそろ行きましょうか
This will have a great effect on our economy!
これすごい経済効果ありますよ
はい
Yes, sir.
Anyway, Yuno, you're amazing.
にしてもいうの お前はすげぇな
どうして
Why?
俺の知らないうちに
While I wasn't watching,
you negotiated with the Kai Empire and discovered a valuable jewel.
戒の商団と交渉したり 値打ちもんの宝石を発見したり
私は何もしてないよ
I didn't do anything.
But you...
だって お前...
私は試合中
During the competition, I simply served tea to a guest that the king introduced me to.
陛下が紹介してくださったお客様にお茶をお出ししただけよ
I chose your outfit, but the king suggested you wear the stones.
衣装を見立てたのは私だけど
石を身に着けるように提案されたのは陛下だし
陛下はどこに
Where is the king?!
The king has left.
陛下ならお帰りになったよ
帰った
He left?!
まったく あなたというお方は
You're unbelievable.
How much of that did you plan?
一体どこまで計算されていたのか
だってもったいないと思いません
Don't you think it's a waste?
自分がどれ程民に影響力があるかを知らず
He lounges around his castle, unaware of the influence he has over his people.
日々お城でくすぶっているなんて
地の部族はよく分かりません
I don't understand the Earth Tribe.
What's so great about that rude man?
あんな不作法な男の何がいいんだか
私は好きですよ グンテ将軍
I like General Geun-tae.
そして ますます彼が欲しくなりました
And now I want him even more.
もし
If we're eventually forced to go to war,
いずれ本当に戦という手段を取らざるを得なくなった時
the Earth Tribe forces he leads will be the most spirited among the five tribes.
彼が率いる地の部族兵の士気は恐らく五部族一でしょう
その勢いは必ずや高華国の力となる
Their intensity will be a great asset to Kouka Kingdom.
He really left.
本当に帰りやがった
I knew it. That pretender lost intentionally.
あんなすっとぼけ王め やっぱりわざと負けやがったな
全てこれが狙いだったのか
Everything he did was for this purpose.
The war games,
戦ごっこも 茶畑や鉱山を見学してたのも 全て
his visits to the tea plantation and the mine, everything.
For a boy so young, that was damned interesting!
若造のくせに おもしれぇことしやがる
お蔭で 地心が潤っちまうじゃねぇか バカヤロ
You're going to make Chishin rich, you idiot!
やはりあの目は見間違いではなかった
I wasn't wrong about his eyes.
緩く見せかけて 底知れぬ熱を腹に抱えてやがる眼差しだ
He pretends to be weak, but his eyes burn with unfathomable heat.
In some ways, he's more terrifying than Lord Yu-hon.
ある意味 ユホン様より恐ろしい
なかなか見所がある男だ
He's a promising man.
奴に期待してもよいのか
Can I place my hopes in him?
なに いずれ会いに行けば はっきりすすことよ
Well, it'll all become clear when I go to see him eventually.
Crying tears for the days that won't return
modoranai hibi ni namida koboshite
You look up to the sky, and it's burning bright red
miageta sora ga akaku akaku moeru
Now that you know your own strength and weakness
jibun no tsuyosa yowasa kizuketa no nara ima
You should have no fear and go where your heart takes you
kimi yo osoreruna kokoro omomuku mama
Cleaving through the wind, your path is lit
kaze wo kirisusumu sono tabiji wo
By the dawn
akatsuki ga terasu
(Gather, fierce arm)
(tsudoe takeki kaina)
(All-seeing eyes)
(senri no hitomi)
Feet that dash through the sky
sora wo kakeyuku ashi
(Shield of eternity)
(kuon no tate)
Fulfill the ancient vows
inishie no chikai ima hatashite
O night, break into dawn
yoru yo akete yuke
Next Time
逃げ切って見せるさ 定めから
I will escape my destiny.
緋龍王が現れたって 僕は蹴り飛ばして見せるよ
Even if King Hiryuu appears, I will kick him away.
次回 暁のヨナ 第十七話
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 17:
Episode 17:      The Pirates of Awa
阿波の海賊
The Pirates of Awa.